

Lisboa, Portugal

scralowrealow@gmail.com https://anadebarros.github.io

in ana-de-barros-4750998 BIOGRAPHY

I'm a science communicator from Lisbon with a solid experience in team management and strategic communication planning. Avid learner, curiosity and passion are my main driving forces to keep improving everyday. With a strong background in science and biomedical research, I soon understood I love to deconstruct the complexity of science so that others can fall in love with it like I did. I have worked as the Director of Science Communication at iMM Lisboa, where I've developed and implemented a new communication strategy that has proved innovative, fruitful and long-lasting.

I've also worked as a science writer and currently serve as a science managing editor at Bio News, where we engage with patient communities, and inform the general public on the latest news in clinical and preclinical research, with a focus in rare diseases.

EXPERIENCE

Managing Scientific Editor

BioNews Services, 2017-present Managing and editing scientific content for several wehsites

COMMUNICATION OFFICER

iMM Lisboa, 2016 -2017

Responsible for restructuring and leading the communication unit. Developed new digital strategy.

Managing Scientific Editor

BioNews Services, 2015-2016

Managing and editing scientific content for several websites.

Managing Scientific Writer

BioNews Services, 2014-2015

Scientific writing on different research topics.

Post Doc Researcher

iMM Lisboa, 2013-2014

Research in immunology and breast cancer.

EDUCATION

WEB AND MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

FLAG Lisboa, 2016 - Present

Learned about website and web app development, front-end and back-end & Android/iOS development.

PHD IMMUNOLOGY

University of Lisbon, 2007 - 2011

PhD thesis on the role of CD27 in gamma-delta T cell development.

MSc Biomolecular Archaeology

University of Manchester, 2005 - 2006

MSc thesis on quantitative real-time PCR for ancient DNA amplification.

Bsc Genetics

University of Newcastle, 2002 - 2005

Publications 2018 Cancer Immune Res PMID: 29358174 | 2012 J Immunol PMID: 22732586 | 2011 Cell Mol Life Sci PMID: 21541698 | 2011 Eur J Immun PMID: 21182090 | 2010 Eur J Immun PMID: 19877017 | 2009 Nature PMID: 19270712 | 2009 PloSone PMID: 19479075

Awards

2007 FCT PhD Scholarship | 2009 Best Immunology Paper Award, Portuguese Immunology Society | 2010 International Research Award CESPU | 2010 Best Poster Award, Portuguese Immunology Society | 2013 FCT Postdoctoral fellowship